Paula Andrea Quintero Celis

Toronto, Canada +1 905 325 2562 pauquinc@gmail.com

Languages: Spanish (native), English (advanced), French (intermediate), Portuguese (Intermediate)

Social communicator with experience in editing and managing editorial projects, from quotation to budget execution. Among his technical skills is the handling of programs such as InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Audition and word processing software as MS office, WordPress and Content Management Systems. I consider myself a responsible, proactive person with great creativity and teamwork ability.

Work experience

Academic Papers Reviewer in Javeriana University Publisher, Bogotá, CO (March 2020 - December 2021) In this position, I evaluated the articles that begin the publication process to identify promptly any inconveniences and faults that may delay the editorial process. Also, I was responsible for advising the Coordination of Journals in the creation and reformulation of editorial policies, formats and procedures.

Proofreader and Editor in Javeriana University Publisher, Bogotá, CO (August 2016 - February 2021): As a proofreader, I corrected spelling, lexical, and syntax errors in texts, apply typographic resources, unified editorial criteria and adapt the text according to the style manual designated for each publication. As an editor, I was in charge of budgeting the project, overseeing the stages of the process and making sure that the resources were properly executed.

Instructional designer in Didacsis, Bogotá, CO (August 2019 - March 2020): I proposed the line of argument for virtual courses. The above, taking into account the objectives and needs of customers. Also, I conceived the animations, videos, infographics, activities, among others audiovisual and pedagogical resources for the courses. Editor in Manuela Beltrán University, Bogotá, CO (August 2017 - July 2018): In this position, I evaluated academic and business texts in Spanish and English and adapted them according to the stylebook. Additionally, I established constant communication with the authors and conducted test audits for both print and digital products. Also, I structured documents, wrote and complemented reports and proposals for virtual courses of the university and the different calls or activities in which it subscribed.

Communication assistant in Colegio Bilingüe Richmond, Bogotá, CO (January 2017 - June 2017): In this position, I supported the marketing efforts of the school and designed graphic pieces with important information for the educational community. In addition, I established communication with suppliers and clients and assisted in events organization.

Marketing assistant in Javeriana University Publisher, Bogotá, CO (August 2017 - July 2018): I periodically updated the website of the Javeriana University Publisher through CMS with the editorial news, I generated content in the different social networks of the organization and made announcements for the presentation of the publisher in several events, I supported the logistics of the events programmed by the organization. Additionally, I created the script for the cultural program from A to Z and assisted in the production of the publisher's monthly newsletter.

Technical manual editor in Coregroup, Bogotá, CO (November 2014 - February 2016): Work carried out: write the text of the user manuals aimed at the clients of the applications developed by the company. I also monitored all stages of the editorial process.

Education

Diploma in Computer Programming. Seneca College. Toronto, Canadá (2021-present). Master in Education. Universidad de Los Andes. Bogotá, Colombia (2018-2022). Bachelor of Social Communication. Pontificia Universidad Javeriana. Bogotá, Colombia (2012-2016).

References

- Paola Castillo Pedraza, Geotechnical Engineer Intern at Intertek PSI. Orlando, United States. Email: ingpcast@gmail.com. Phone +1 352 328 5743
- Nicolás Morales Thomas, Director and senior editor at Javeriana University Publisher. Bogotá,
 Colombia. Email: nicolas.morales@javeriana.edu.co. Phone +57 315 8900749